In this lesson, Harrison will teach the most important key building block of LLM, namely
在本课中，哈里森将教授法学硕士最重要的关键构建块，即
the chain.
链条。
The chain usually combines an LLM large language model together with a prompt, and with this
该链通常将LLM大型语言模型与提示组合在一起，并且与此
building block, you can also put a bunch of these building blocks together to carry out
构件，你也可以把一堆这些构件放在一起进行
a sequence of operations on your text or on your other data.
对文本或其他数据的操作序列。
I'm excited to dive into it.
我很高兴能深入研究它。
All right, to start, we're going to load the environment variables as we have before, and
好的，首先，我们将像以前一样加载环境变量，并且
then we're also going to load some data that we're going to use.
然后，我们还将加载一些我们将要使用的数据。
So part of the power of these chains is that you can run them over many inputs at a time.
因此，这些链的部分功能在于您可以一次在多个输入上运行它们。
Here we're going to load a pandas data frame.
在这里，我们将加载一个熊猫数据框。
A pandas data frame is just a data structure that contains a bunch of different elements
熊猫数据框只是一个包含一堆不同元素的数据结构
of data.
的数据。
If you're not familiar with pandas, don't worry about it.
如果你不熟悉熊猫，不用担心。
The main point here is that we're loading some data that we can then use later on.
这里的重点是我们正在加载一些数据，然后我们可以稍后使用。
So if we look inside this pandas data frame, we can see that there is a product column
因此，如果我们查看这个熊猫数据框内部，我们可以看到有一个产品列
and then a review column.
然后是评论列。
Each of these rows is a different data point that we can start passing through our chains.
这些行中的每一行都是一个不同的数据点，我们可以开始通过我们的链传递。
So the first chain we're going to cover is the LLM chain.
因此，我们要介绍的第一个链是LLM链。
This is a simple but really powerful chain that underpins a lot of the chains that we'll
这是一个简单但非常强大的链，它支撑着我们将要的许多链。
go over in the future.
以后再过去。
So we're going to import three different things.
因此，我们将导入三种不同的东西。
We're going to import the OpenAI model, so the LLM.
我们将导入OpenAI模型，因此LLM。
We're going to import the chat prompt template, so this is the prompt.
我们将导入聊天提示模板，所以这是提示。
And then we're going to import the LLM chain.
然后我们将导入LLM链。
And so first what we're going to do is we're going to initialize the language model that
因此，首先我们要做的是初始化语言模型
we want to use.
我们想使用。
So we're going to initialize the chat OpenAI with a high temperature so that we can get
因此，我们将在高温下初始化聊天OpenAI，以便我们可以获得
some fun descriptions.
一些有趣的描述。
Now we're going to initialize a prompt, and this prompt is going to take in a variable
现在我们要初始化一个提示，这个提示将接受一个变量。
called product.
称为产品。
It's going to ask the LLM to generate what the best name is to describe a company that
它将要求LLM生成描述一家公司的最佳名称
makes that product.
制造该产品。
And then finally we're going to combine these two things into a chain.
最后，我们将把这两件事组合成一个链。
And so this is what we call an LLM chain, and it's quite simple.
这就是我们所说的LLM链，它非常简单。
It's just the combination of the LLM and the prompt.
这只是LLM和提示的组合。
But now this chain will let us run through the prompt and into the LLM in a sequential
但是现在这个链将让我们依次运行提示并进入LLM
manner.
方式。
And so if we have a product called queen size sheet set, we can run this through the chain
因此，如果我们有一个名为女王尺寸床单套装的产品，我们可以将其贯穿整个链条。
by using chain.run.
通过使用chain.run。
And what this will do is it will format the prompt under the hood, and then it will pass
这将做的是它将格式化引擎盖下的提示，然后它会通过
the whole prompt into the LLM.
整个提示进入LLM。
And so we can see that we get back the name of this hypothetical company called Royal
所以我们可以看到，我们找回了这家名为Royal的假想公司的名字。
Beddings.
床上用品。
And so here would be a good time to pause, and you can input any product descriptions
所以这里是暂停的好时机，你可以输入任何产品描述。
that you would want, and you can see what the chain will output as a result.
你想要的，你可以看到链将输出什么结果。
So the LLM chain is the most basic type of chain, and that's going to be used a lot in
所以LLM链是最基本的链类型，这将在
the future.
未来。
And so we can see how this will be used in the next type of chain, which will be sequential
因此，我们可以看到这将如何在下一种类型的链中使用，这将是顺序的
chains.
链。
And so sequential chains run a sequence of chains one after another.
因此，顺序链一个接一个地运行一系列链。
So to start, you're going to import the simple sequential chain.
因此，首先，您将导入简单的顺序链。
And this works well when we have sub chains that expect only one input and return only
当我们有只期望一个输入并只返回的子链时，这很有效
one output.
一个输出。
And so here we're going to first create one chain, which uses an LLM and a prompt.
所以在这里，我们将首先创建一个链，它使用LLM和提示。
And this prompt is going to take in the product and will return the best name to describe
此提示将接受产品，并将返回要描述的最佳名称
that company.
那家公司。
So that will be the first chain.
所以这将是第一条链。
Then we're going to create a second chain.
然后我们将创建第二个链。
And this second chain will take in the company name and then output a 20-word description
第二个链将接收公司名称，然后输出一个 20 个单词的描述
of that company.
的那家公司。
And so you can imagine how these chains might want to be run one after another, where the
所以你可以想象这些链可能想要一个接一个地运行，其中
output of the first chain, the company name, is then passed into the second chain.
然后，第一个链的输出（公司名称）将传递到第二个链中。
We can easily do this by creating a simple sequential chain where we have the two chains
我们可以通过创建一个简单的顺序链来轻松做到这一点，其中我们有两条链
described there.
在那里描述。
And we'll call this overall simple chain.
我们将这个整体称为简单链。
Now what you can do is run this chain over any product description.
现在，您可以做的是在任何产品描述上运行此链。
And so if we use it with the product above, the queen size sheet set, we can run it over
因此，如果我们将其与上面的产品一起使用，大号床单套装，我们可以将其运行
and we can see that it first outputs royal betting.
我们可以看到它首先输出皇家投注。
And then it passes it into the second chain and it comes up with this description of what
然后它把它传递到第二个链中，它提出了这个描述
that company could be about.
那家公司可能是关于。
The simple sequential chain works well when there's only a single input and a single output.
当只有一个输入和一个输出时，简单的顺序链效果很好。
But what about when there are multiple inputs or multiple outputs?
但是，当有多个输入或多个输出时呢？
And so we can do this by using just the regular sequential chain.
因此，我们可以仅使用常规顺序链来做到这一点。
So let's import that and then you're going to create a bunch of chains that we're going
因此，让我们导入它，然后您将创建一堆我们要创建的链。
to use one after another.
一个接一个地使用。
We're going to be using the data from above, which has a review.
我们将使用上面的数据，这些数据有一个审查。
And so the first chain, we're going to take the review and translate it into English.
所以第一个链条，我们将进行审查并将其翻译成英文。
With the second chain, we're going to create a summary of that review in one sentence.
在第二个链中，我们将用一句话创建该评论的摘要。
And this will use the previously generated English review.
这将使用先前生成的英语评论。
The third chain is going to detect what the language of the review was in the first place.
第三条链将首先检测评论的语言是什么。
And so if you notice, this is using the review variable that is coming from the original
因此，如果您注意到，这是使用来自原始的 review 变量
review.
回顾。
And finally, the fourth chain will take in multiple inputs.
最后，第四条链将接受多个输入。
So this will take in the summary variable, which we calculated with the second chain,
因此，这将采用我们用第二条链计算的汇总变量，
and the language variable, which we calculated with the third chain.
以及语言变量，我们使用第三条链计算。
And it's going to ask for a follow-up response to the summary in the specified language.
它将要求以指定的语言对摘要进行后续响应。
One important thing to note about all these subchains is that the input keys and output
关于所有这些子链，需要注意的一件重要事情是输入键和输出
keys need to be pretty precise.
键需要非常精确。
So here we're taking in review.
因此，我们在这里进行审查。
This is a variable that will be passed in at the start.
这是一个将在开始时传入的变量。
We can see that we explicitly set the output key to English review.
我们可以看到，我们明确地将输出键设置为英语复习。
This is then used in the next prompt down below, where we take in English review with
然后在下面的下一个提示中使用，我们将在其中进行英语审查
that same variable name.
相同的变量名称。
And we set the output key of that chain to summary, which we can see is used in the final
我们将该链的输出键设置为 summary，我们可以看到它在最终中使用
chain.
链。
The third prompt takes in review, the original variable, and output language, which is again
第三个提示接受查看、原始变量和输出语言，这又是
used in the final prompt.
在最终提示中使用。
It's really important to get these variable names lined up exactly right, because there's
让这些变量名称完全正确排列非常重要，因为有
so many different inputs and outputs going on.
许多不同的输入和输出正在进行中。
And if you get any key errors, you should definitely check that they are lined up so.
如果您遇到任何关键错误，您绝对应该检查它们是否排列在一起。
The simple sequential chain takes in multiple chains, where each one has a single input
简单的顺序链接受多个链，其中每个链都有一个输入
and a single output.
和单个输出。
To see a visual representation of this, we can look at the slide, where it has one chain
要查看此内容的可视化表示，我们可以查看幻灯片，其中有一个链
feeding into the other chain, one after another.
一个接一个地进入另一条链条。
Here we can see a visual description of the sequential chain.
在这里，我们可以看到顺序链的视觉描述。
Comparing it to the above chain, you can notice that any step in the chain can take in multiple
将其与上面的链条进行比较，您可以注意到链中的任何步骤都可以包含多个
input variables.
输入变量。
This is useful when you have more complicated downstream chains that need to be a composition
当您有更复杂的下游链需要组合时，这很有用
of multiple previous chains.
之前的多个链。
Now that we have all these chains, we can easily combine them in the sequential chain.
现在我们有了所有这些链，我们可以轻松地将它们组合到顺序链中。
So you'll notice here that we'll pass in the four chains we created into the chains variable.
所以你会注意到，我们将把我们创建的四个链传递到链变量中。
We'll create the inputs variable with the one human input, which is the review.
我们将使用一个人工输入创建输入变量，即评论。
And then we want to return all the intermediate outputs.
然后我们要返回所有中间输出。
So the English review, the summary, and then the follow-up message.
所以英文评论，总结，然后是后续信息。
Now we can run this over some of the data.
现在我们可以对一些数据运行它。
So let's choose a review and pass it in through the overall chain.
因此，让我们选择一个评论并将其传递到整个链条中。
We can see here that the original review looks like it was in French.
我们可以在这里看到，原始评论看起来像是法语。
We can see the English review as a translation.
我们可以将英文评论视为翻译。
We can see a summary of that review, and then we can see a follow-up message in the original
我们可以看到该评论的摘要，然后我们可以看到原始中的后续消息
language of French.
法语。
You should pause the video here and try putting in different inputs.
您应该在此处暂停视频并尝试输入不同的输入。
So far we've covered the LLM chain and then a sequential chain.
到目前为止，我们已经介绍了LLM链，然后是顺序链。
But what if you want to do something more complicated?
但是，如果您想做更复杂的事情怎么办？
A pretty common but basic operation is to route an input to a chain depending on what
一个非常常见但基本的操作是根据什么将输入路由到链
exactly that input is.
正是该输入。
A good way to imagine this is if you have multiple subchains, each of which specialized
想象这一点的一个好方法是，如果你有多个子链，每个子链都是专门的。
for a particular type of input, you could have a router chain, which first decides which
对于特定类型的输入，您可以有一个路由器链，它首先决定哪个
subchain to pass it to and then passes it to that chain.
将其传递到的子链，然后将其传递给该链。
For a concrete example, let's look at where we are routing between different types of
对于一个具体的例子，让我们看看我们在不同类型的
chains depending on the subject that seems to come in.
链条取决于似乎进入的主题。
So we have here different prompts.
所以我们这里有不同的提示。
One prompt is good for answering physics questions.
一个提示非常适合回答物理问题。
The second prompt is good for answering math questions.
第二个提示适合回答数学问题。
The third for history.
第三个是历史。
And then a fourth for computer science.
然后是计算机科学的第四个。
Let's define all these prompt templates.
让我们定义所有这些提示模板。
After we have these prompt templates, we can then provide more information about them.
有了这些提示模板后，我们可以提供有关它们的更多信息。
We can give each one a name and then a description.
我们可以给每个人一个名字，然后是一个描述。
This description for the physics one is good for answering questions about physics.
这种对物理学的描述有利于回答有关物理学的问题。
This information is going to be passed to the router chain.
此信息将被传递到路由器链。
So the router chain can decide when to use this subchain.
因此，路由器链可以决定何时使用此子链。
Let's now import the other types of chains that we need.
现在让我们导入我们需要的其他类型的链。
Here we need a multi-prompt chain.
这里我们需要一个多提示链。
This is a specific type of chain that is used when routing between multiple different prompt
这是一种特定类型的链，在多个不同的提示之间路由时使用
templates.
模板。
As you can see, all the options we have are prompt templates themselves.
如您所见，我们拥有的所有选项本身都是提示模板。
But this is just one type of thing that you can route between.
但这只是您可以在其中路由的一种类型。
You can route between any type of chain.
您可以在任何类型的链之间路由。
The other classes that we'll implement here are an LLM router chain.
我们将在这里实现的其他类是LLM路由器链。
This uses a language model itself to route between the different subchains.
这使用语言模型本身在不同的子链之间路由。
This is where the description and the name provided above will be used.
这是将使用上面提供的描述和名称的地方。
We'll also import a router output parser.
我们还将导入路由器输出解析器。
This parses the LLM output into a dictionary that can be used downstream to determine which
这会将 LLM 输出解析为一个字典，该字典可以在下游用于确定哪个
chain to use and what the input to that chain should be.
要使用的链以及该链的输入应该是什么。
Now we can get around to using it.
现在我们可以开始使用它了。
First let's import and define the language model that we will use.
首先，让我们导入并定义我们将使用的语言模型。
We now create the destination chains.
我们现在创建目标链。
These are the chains that will be called by the router chain.
这些是路由器链将调用的链。
As you can see, each destination chain itself is a language model chain, an LLM chain.
如您所见，每个目标链本身都是一个语言模型链，一个LLM链。
In addition to the destination chains, we also need a default chain.
除了目标链，我们还需要一个默认链。
This is a chain that's called when the router can't decide which of the subchains to use.
这是当路由器无法决定使用哪个子链时调用的链。
In the example above, this might be called when the input question has nothing to do
在上面的示例中，当输入问题无关时，可能会调用它
with physics, math, history, or computer science.
物理、数学、历史或计算机科学。
Now we define the template that is used by the LLM to route between the different chains.
现在我们定义LLM用于在不同链之间路由的模板。
This has instructions of the task to be done as well as the specific formatting that the
这包含要完成的任务的说明以及特定的格式
output should be in.
输出应为 in。
Let's put a few of these pieces together to build the router chain.
让我们把其中的一些部分放在一起来构建路由器链。
First we create the full router template by formatting it with the destinations that we
首先，我们通过用我们的目的地格式化它来创建完整的路由器模板
defined above.
上面定义。
This template is flexible to a bunch of different types of destinations.
此模板可灵活地用于许多不同类型的目的地。
One thing you can do here is pause and add different types of destinations.
您可以在此处做的一件事是暂停并添加不同类型的目的地。
So up here, rather than just physics, math, history, and computer science, you could add
所以在这里，不仅仅是物理、数学、历史和计算机科学，你可以添加
a different subject like English or Latin.
不同的主题，如英语或拉丁语。
Next we create the prompt template from this template and then we create the router chain
接下来，我们从此模板创建提示模板，然后创建路由器链
by passing in the LLM and the overall router prompt.
通过传入 LLM 和整个路由器提示符。
Note that here we have the router output parser.
请注意，这里有路由器输出解析器。
This is important as it will help this chain decide which subchains to route between.
这很重要，因为它将帮助该链决定在哪些子链之间路由。
And finally, putting it all together, we can create the overall chain.
最后，将它们放在一起，我们可以创建整个链条。
This has a router chain which is defined here.
这有一个此处定义的路由器链。
It has destination chains which we pass in here and then we also pass in the default
它有目标链，我们在这里传入，然后我们也传入默认值
chain.
链。
We can now use this chain.
我们现在可以使用这个链。
So let's ask it some questions.
所以让我们问它一些问题。
If we ask it a question about physics, we should hopefully see that it is routed to
如果我们问它一个关于物理学的问题，我们应该希望看到它被路由到
the physics chain with the input, what is blackbody radiation, and then that is passed
带有输入的物理链，什么是黑体辐射，然后传递
into the chain down below and we can see that the response is very detailed with lots of
进入下面的链，我们可以看到响应非常详细，有很多
physics details.
物理细节。
You should pause the video here and try putting in different inputs.
您应该在此处暂停视频并尝试输入不同的输入。
You can try with all the other types of special chains that we have defined above.
您可以尝试使用我们上面定义的所有其他类型的特殊链。
So for example, if we ask it a math question, we should see that it's routed to the math
例如，如果我们问它一个数学问题，我们应该看到它被路由到数学
chain and then passed into that.
链，然后进入那个。
We can also see what happens when we pass in a question that is not related to any of
我们还可以看到当我们传入与任何问题无关的问题时会发生什么
the subchains.
子链。
So here we ask it a question about biology and we can see the chain that it chooses is
所以在这里我们问它一个关于生物学的问题，我们可以看到它选择的链是
none.
没有。
This means that it will be passed to the default chain which itself is just a generic call
这意味着它将被传递给默认链，该链本身只是一个泛型调用
to the language model.
到语言模型。
The language model luckily knows a lot about biology so it can help us out here.
幸运的是，语言模型对生物学了解很多，所以它可以在这里帮助我们。
Now that we've covered these basic building blocks types of chains, we can start to put
现在我们已经介绍了这些基本的构建块类型的链，我们可以开始放置
them together to create really interesting applications.
它们一起创建真正有趣的应用程序。
For example, in the next section, we're going to cover how to create a chain that can do
例如，在下一节中，我们将介绍如何创建一个可以
question answering over your documents.
对您的文件进行问答。